# **JACOB COLVIN**

#### Platform, Site Reliability, and Software Engineer

#### **ABOUT**

With over seven years of experience in the tech industry, my expertise lies in **Site Reliability Engineering**, enriched by a deep focus in **Software** and **Platform Engineering**. My passion lies in building robust **developer platforms**, crafting maintainable **infrastructure as code**, and architecting systems in a way that is simple and straightforward. My experience as a developer, with a focus on **Go** and **Python**, enables my ability to create platforms that are not only reliable, but also enjoyable to use.

# **EDUCATION**

## B.S. Information Technology University of Cincinnati - CECH

- **Aug** 2015 April 2020
- · Cybersecurity specialization
- Summa Cum Laude

#### **SKILLS**

Infrastructure: AKS K3s Talos Azure Cilium Terraform Ansible Helm Crossplane Cloud Foundry
Development: Go Python FastAPI TypeScript Jsonnet Profiling OpenTelemetry PowerShell Bash Make
Observability: Prometheus Thanos Grafana Jaeger Loki Vector Fluentd OpenTelemetry Datadog
Azure Managed: Databricks Datafactory Postgres Key Vault Storage Account
DevOps/GitOps: FluxCD ArgoCD GitHub Actions Azure DevOps

### **EXPERIENCE**

84.51° / The Kroger Company	Remote / Cincinnati, Ohio	May 2016 - Current
Senior Site Reliability Engineer (Kubernetes)		☐ January 2023 - Current

- Redesigned large parts of our IaC (Terraform, Flux) for Kubernetes (AKS), reducing manual toil by 200+ hours per year, to support increased scaling demands of new production workloads (driving \$300MM+ operating profit).
- Developed **Python** application for scaffolding template repositories, as well as centralized **Helm charts** and related **GitHub Actions**, which collectively saved developers 3000+ hours during the first year in production.
- Led Datadog cost-saving efforts which reduced spend by over \$400k per year; enforced controls using Terraform.
- Participated in an on-call rotation for our production Kubernetes clusters; ensured compliance with SLAs.
- Empowered developers to efficiently and independently troubleshoot their applications by acting as lead subject-matter expert for observability platforms; headed support and maintenance of all observability tooling, including **Datadog**, **Grafana**, **Prometheus**, **Thanos**, **Jaeger**, **OpenTelemetry Collectors**, and **Vector**.

#### 

- Deployed and supported enterprise observability services/tooling, utilizing **Ansible** (on-premises) and **Flux** (Azure Kubernetes), including **Grafana**, **Prometheus**, **Thanos**, **Fluentd**, **Telegraf**, and **Jaeger**.
- Developed **Python** library to centralize instrumentation for **Prometheus** metrics, **OpenTelemetry** tracing, structured logging, and **pprof** profiling, with support for **FastAPI**, **Databricks** notebooks, and more, which both delivered a positive and consistent experience with our observability platforms, and directly saved developers a collective 1000+ hours.
- Led development of multiple **Prometheus exporters** using **Go**, utilizing **Redis** for caching, distributed workers with pub/sub and leader election, **CEL** for custom rule evaluation, **Cue** and custom tooling for validation, and Go text templating.
- Rolled out **Datadog** as a unified logging platform for both **Azure** and on-premises systems, using **Terraform** for configuration and **Fluentd** for log parsing and forwarding; enabled deprecation of multiple disparate logging solutions.
- Created multiple Jsonnet libraries for Prometheus and Alertmanager configuration, saving 100+ hours per year.
- Contributed small fixes to Grafana, Thanos, Jaeger, and other upstream Git repositories.

Versatilist Engineer	📋 January 2020 - March 2021
• Created and administered multiple <b>Azure</b> environments using <b>Terraform</b> in Azuresources such as <b>Databricks</b> workspaces, <b>Datafactory</b> instances, <b>Key Vaults</b> ,	
• Enhanced our <b>Prometheus</b> ecosystem by adding high-availability and long-ter Prometheus to track SLOs and KPIs over years instead of days.	rm storage via <b>Thanos</b> , thus allowing consumers of
• Assisted a mix of seven development and data science teams with <b>Azure</b> migra alerts, <b>GitHub Actions</b> , and <b>Azure DevOps</b> pipelines; acted as technical liaison	
ICT Co-op	☐ May 2016 – December 2019
• Designed a <b>C#</b> API layer over several legacy systems, and a SPA using <b>TypeS</b> improve velocity towards deprecation of legacy systems.	Script with React, to both assist with support, and
• Created a <b>Prometheus exporter</b> for <b>SonarQube</b> data, along with correspond team to gather relevant KPIs.	ing dashboards, rules and alerts, to allow security
• Automated <b>Red Hat Linux</b> VM deployment through <b>ServiceNow</b> , via interaction	ns with <b>Satellite</b> , <b>vCenter</b> , <b>SolarWinds</b> and <b>Ansible</b> .
• Designed a custom web framework using <b>PowerShell</b> and <b>Bootstrap</b> for execution and metrics from many distinct products.	cuting administrative tasks and aggregating events
• Automated many miscellaneous tasks using PowerShell, VBA, Bash and PL, workflows with Bash and SAS ODS.	/SQL in Bash; created and documented Automic
• Interfaced with BOSH and Hadoop to design custom Pivotal Cloud Foundry r	monitoring solution.
KEY PROJECTS	
OmegaGraf	jacobcolvin.com/OmegaGraf
• An open-source project that seeks to completely automate vCenter monitoring including Telegraf, Prometheus, and Grafana.	g, by orchestrating a small ecosystem of containers,
Paper: https://scholar.uc.edu/concern/student_works/jw827c971	
• Technologies: Docker, C# / .NET Core, TypeScript, React	
Homelab	• MacroPower/homelab
• Infrastructure-as-code for my homelab / personal cloud. Defines multiple into bare metal (Talos) and multiple Hetzner cloud environments (k3s-on-MicroOS)	
Technologies: Talos, Cilium, ArgoCD, Helm, Jsonnet, Terraform	
Prometheus Video Renderer	• MacroPower/prometheus_video_renderer
• Just for fun, completely impractical tool that allows you to encode audio and v	video as Prometheus metrics.
Featured on the Grafana blog: https://grafana.com/blog/2021/07/30/how-to-use-grafana-and-prometheus	s-to-rickroll-your-friends-or-enemies
Technologies: Go, Jsonnet	
Analytics Panel Plugin	• MacroPower/macropower-analytics-panel
• Grafana panel plugin that injects JavaScript into dashboards, which reports used in turn exports Prometheus metrics for display in (you guessed it) Grafana.	r session information to a backend Go server, which
Over 1MM downloads, featured by Giant Swarm: https://www.giantswarm.io/blog/grafana-ception-or-how-we-do-grafana-ana-	alytics-giant-swarm
Technologies: TypeScript, React, Go	
Wakatime Exporter	MacroPower/wakatime_exporter

- Prometheus exporter and Grafana dashboards for Wakatime coding statistics.
- Over 100k downloads
- Technologies: Go